Inventory to the J. C. Hurewitz papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Subject file, 1920-1981
  - Palestine (British mandate), 1938-1948
    - Political coalitions and rivalries, 1942-1947 (Box-folder 80: 1)
    - Population trends, 1937-1947 (Box-folder 80: 2)
    - Press, 1942-1947
      - Jewish, 1942-1947 (Box-folder 80: 3)
      - United States, 1944-1947 (Box-folder 80: 4)
    - United Nations reports, 1947 (Box-folder 80: 5-6)
    - War effort, 1940-1945
      - Arab contribution, 1942-1944 (Box-folder 80: 7)
      - Jewish contribution, 1940-1945 (Box-folder 80: 8)
    - White Paper, 1939-1945 (Box-folder 80: 9)
  - Palestine Liberation Organization, 1978-1981 (Box-folder 81: 1)
  - Saudi Arabia, 1978 (Box-folder 81: 2)
  - Soviet Union, 1979-1980 (Box-folder 81: 3)
  - Sudan, 1924-1925 (Box-folder 81: 4)
  - Syria, 1942-1978 (Box-folder 81: 5)
  - Theater in the Middle East, 1971 (Box-folder 81: 6)
  - Turkey, 1975-1980 (Box-folder 81: 7)
  - Yemen, 1972 (Box-folder 81: 8)
- Speeches and writings, 1947-1992
  - "What Are Our National Interests in Palestine?,", 1947 (Box-folder 81: 9)
  - "The Problem of the Arab Refugees,", 1950 (Box-folder 81: 10)
  - Reviews of Middle East Dilemmas, 1953 (Box-folder 81: 11)
  - "The Middle East and Europe, 1798-1914: The Interactive Politics of Hegemony and Survival,", 1961 October (Box-folder 81: 12)
  - Transcript of television interview for CBS News, 1967 May 24 (Box-folder 81: 13)
  - Transcript of television interview conducted by Edwin Newman for NBC News, 1967 December 6 (Box-folder 81: 14)
  - Transcript of interview conducted by a Japanese journalist, 1975 (Box-folder 81: 15)
  - The Middle East and North Africa in World Politics: A Documentary Record, projected volume three, 1977-1992
    - Correspondence, 1982-1992 (Box-folder 82: 1)
    - Notes, 1979-1982 (Box-folder 82: 2)
    - Drafts of tables of contents, 1977-1980
      - 1977 (Box-folder 82: 3)
      - 1978-1980 (Box-folder 82: 4)
    - Transcribed and translated documents, 1977-1982 (originals dated 1945-1946) (Box-folder 82: 5-8)
    - Transcribed and translated documents, 1977-1982 (originals dated 1946-1958) (Box-folder 83: 1-8)
- Academic career file, 1949-1992
  - Correspondence, 1949-1992
    - General, 1963-1992
      - 1963-1984 (Box-folder 84: 1)
      - 1985-1992 (Box-folder 84: 2)
    - Aspen Institute for Humanistic Studies, 1975 (Box-folder 84: 3)
    - Bar-On, Mordechai, 1961-1963 (Box-folder 84: 4)
    - Publishers of books critiqued by Hurewitz, 1949-1953 (Box-folder 84: 5)
    - RIAS-Berlin, 1968 (Box-folder 84: 6)
    - Rosenne, Shabtai, 1961 (Box-folder 84: 7)
    - U.S. State Department and National Archives, 1975-1980 (Box-folder 84: 8)
  - Lecture notes, 1950-1952
    - 1950 (Box-folder 84: 9)
    - 1951-1952 (Box-folder 84: 10)
  - Memoranda and reports prepared for the Council on Foreign Relations, 1951-1952 (Box-folder 84: 11)
  - Microfilming schedule for Turkish archives, 1960 (Box-folder 85: 1)
  - Public Record Office file, 1974-1988
    - Correspondence, 1974-1982 (Box-folder 85: 2)
    - Logs of requested documents, 1985-1988
      - 1985 (Box-folder 85: 3-6)
      - 1986 (Box-folder 85: 7)
      - 1987 (Box-folder 85: 8-11)
      - 1988 (Box-folder 85: 12-13)
    - Notes, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 85: 14)
    - Summaries of conversations with officials and historians, 1961-1970 (Box-folder 85: 15)
    - Translations of treaties and decrees relating to the Russian Empire, 1960 (Box-folder 85: 16)
- Printed matter relating to Palestine, the Middle East, and North Africa, 1922-1957
  - Maps, 1955 (Box-folder 86: 1)
  - Memoranda, papers, and reports, 1922-1957
    - General, 1922-1946 (Box-folder 86: 2)
    - American Jewish Committee, 1948-1951
      - 1948 (Box-folder 86: 3)
      - 1949 (Box-folder 86: 4)
      - 1950 (Box-folder 86: 5)
      - 1951 (Box-folder 86: 6)
    - Rockefeller Brothers Fund, 1956-1957 (Box-folder 86: 7)
  - Monographs, 1955 (Box-folder 87: 1-3)
- Photocopies of declassified U.S. government documents, 1944-1961
  - Office of Strategic Services, 1943-1944 (Box-folder 88: 1)
  - National Security Council, 1948-1960
    - 1948 (Box-folder 88: 2)
    - 1949 (Box-folder 88: 3)
    - 1952-1953 (Box-folder 88: 4)
    - 1954 (Box-folder 88: 5-6)
    - 1955 (Box-folder 88: 7)
    - 1956 (Box-folder 88: 8)
    - 1957-1958 (Box-folder 88: 9)
    - 1959-1960 (Box-folder 88: 10)
  - State Department, 1946-1961
    - Letters, memoranda, and telegrams, 1946-1956
      - 1946 (Box-folder 88: 11)
      - 1947 (Box-folder 88: 12)
      - 1948-1949 (Box-folder 89: 1)
      - 1950 (Box-folder 89: 2)
      - 1951 (Box-folder 89: 3-5)
      - 1952 (Box-folder 89: 6-7)
      - 1953 (Box-folder 89: 8)
      - 1954 (Box-folder 89: 9)
      - 1955 (Box-folder 90: 1-3)
      - 1956 (Box-folder 90: 4-9)
    - Reports, 1951-1961
      - 1951 (Box-folder 91: 1)
      - 1953 (Box-folder 91: 2)
      - 1956-1958 (Box-folder 91: 3)
      - 1958 (Box-folder 91: 4-5)
      - 1959 (Box-folder 91: 6)
      - 1960 (Box-folder 91: 7-8)
      - 1961 (Box-folder 91: 9)
- Subject file, 1935-2005
  - Abu Nidal, 1986 (Box-folder 92: 1)
  - Algeria, 1960-1970 (Box-folder 92: 2)
  - Amīn al-Husainī, Grand Mufti, 1985 (Box-folder 92: 3)
  - Bar-Simon-Tov, Yaacov, 1975-1981 (Box-folder 92: 4)
  - Barak, Ehud, 1996-2000
    - 1996-1999 (Box-folder 92: 5)
    - 1999-2000 (Box-folder 92: 6)
    - 2000 (Box-folder 92: 7-8)
    - 2001 (Box-folder 92: 9)
  - Camp David II, 2000 (Box-folder 92: 10-11)
  - Camp David II, 2000 (Box-folder 93: 1-4)
  - Clinton, Bill, 1998 (Box-folder 93: 5)
  - Committee for Accuracy in Middle East Reporting in America (CAMERA), 1995-1999 (Box-folder 93: 6)
  - Ebban, Abba, 1986-1995 (Box-folder 93: 7)
  - Egypt, 1947-2000 (Box-folder 93: 8)
  - European Union, 2001 (Box-folder 93: 9)
  - Final status issues in Middle East peace negotiations, 1996-2000 (Box-folder 93: 10)
  - Friedman, Thomas J., 1995-2005 (Box-folder 93: 11)
  - Gaulle, Charles de, 1964 (Box-folder 93: 12)
  - Golan Heights, 2000 (Box-folder 93: 13)
  - Gold, Dore, 1990-2002 (Box-folder 93: 14)
  - Hamas, 1992-2002 (Box-folder 93: 15)
  - Hebron, 1995-2002 (Box-folder 93: 16)
  - Housseini family, 1944 (Box-folder 94: 1)
  - Iran, 1979-2003
    - 1979-1996 (Box-folder 94: 2)
    - 1997 (Box-folder 94: 3)
    - 1998 (Box-folder 94: 4)
    - 1999 (Box-folder 94: 5-6)
    - 2000 (Box-folder 94: 7-8)
    - 2000-2003 (Box-folder 94: 9-10)
  - Iraq, 1990-2004
    - 1990-1997 (Box-folder 94: 11)
    - 1998 (Box-folder 94: 12-13)
    - 1999 (Box-folder 94: 14-15)
    - 2000 (Box-folder 95: 1)
    - 2000-2001 (Box-folder 95: 2)
    - 2001-2004 (Box-folder 95: 3)
  - Islam, 1989-1997 (Box-folder 95: 4)
  - Israel, 1994-2004
    - 1994-1998 (Box-folder 95: 5)
    - 1998 (Box-folder 95: 6)
    - 2000 (Box-folder 95: 7)
    - 2001 (Box-folder 95: 8-10)
    - 2002 (Box-folder 95: 11)
    - 2002 (Box-folder 96: 1)
    - 2003-2004 (Box-folder 96: 2)
  - Jerusalem, 1935-2002
    - 1935-1979 (Box-folder 96: 3)
    - 1980-1984 (Box-folder 96: 4)
    - 1990 (Box-folder 96: 5)
    - 1992-1994 (Box-folder 96: 6)
    - 1995-1996 (Box-folder 96: 7)
    - 1996 (Box-folder 96: 8-9)
    - 1996-1998 (Box-folder 96: 10)
    - 1999-2002 (Box-folder 96: 11)
  - Jordan, 1979-2001
    - 1979-1991 (Box-folder 97: 1)
    - 1992-2001 (Box-folder 97: 2)
  - Kurds, 1999-2001 (Box-folder 97: 3)
  - Kuwait, 1991-2001 (Box-folder 97: 4)
  - Lebanon, 1982-2001
    - 1982-1996 (Box-folder 97: 5)
    - 1997-2000 (Box-folder 97: 6)
    - 2000 (Box-folder 97: 7-8)
    - 2001 (Box-folder 97: 9)
  - Lewis, Anthony, 1996-2002 (Box-folder 97: 10)
  - Lewis, Bernard, 1976-2002 (Box-folder 97: 11)
  - Libya, 1987-2003 (Box-folder 97: 12)
  - Middle East region, 1996-2001 (Box-folder 97: 13)
  - Military cooperation between the United Staets and Israel, 2000 (Box-folder 97: 14)
  - Mitchell Report, 2001-2002
    - 2001 (Box-folder 98: 1-2)
    - 2001-2002 (Box-folder 98: 3)
  - Morocco, 1999 (Box-folder 98: 4)
  - Morris, Benny, 2000 (Box-folder 98: 5)
  - Nazareth, 1999-2000 (Box-folder 98: 6)
  - Netanyahu, Benjamin, 1996-1998 (Box-folder 98: 7)
  - North Africa, 1954-1959 (Box-folder 98: 8)
  - Oslo peace process, 1994-2001 (Box-folder 98: 9)
  - Palestine Liberation Organization, 1970-2002
    - 1970-1974 (Box-folder 98: 10)
    - 1994-2002 (Box-folder 98: 11)
  - Palestine National Council, 1990 (Box-folder 98: 12)
  - Palestinian Arabs, 1995-2000 (Box-folder 98: 13)
  - Palestine National Authority, 1993-2002
    - 1993-1996 (Box-folder 98: 14)
    - 1997-1999 (Box-folder 98: 15)
    - 2000-2002 (Box-folder 99: 1)
  - Palestinian right of return, 1990-2001 (Box-folder 99: 2)
  - Palestinian self-rule and sovereignty, 1973-2000
    - 1973-1976 (Box-folder 99: 3)
    - 1992-1993 (Box-folder 99: 4)
    - 1994 (Box-folder 99: 5-6)
    - 1994-1995 (Box-folder 99: 7)
    - 1995 (Box-folder 99: 8)
    - 1997 (Box-folder 99: 9-10)
  - Peace process, 1991-2000 (Box-folder 99: 11-12)
  - Petroleum industry, 2000-2001 (Box-folder 99: 13)
  - Qatar, 2000-2001 (Box-folder 99: 14)
  - Religion and state in Israel, 1979-2002
    - 1979 (Box-folder 100: 1)
    - 1988 (Box-folder 100: 2)
    - 1994 (Box-folder 100: 3)
    - 1995-1998 (Box-folder 100: 4-5)
    - 1998-1999 (Box-folder 100: 6)
    - 2000-2002 (Box-folder 100: 7)
  - Russia-Foreign relations, 1998-2002 (Box-folder 100: 8)
  - Said, Edward W., 1974-2002 (Box-folder 100: 9)
  - Saudi Arabia, 1996-2004 (Box-folder 100: 10)
  - Secularism, 1986-1991 (Box-folder 100: 11)
  - Sharm el Sheik agreement, 2000 (Box-folder 100: 12)
  - Sharon, Ariel, 2001 (Box-folder 100: 13)
  - Shepherdstown negotiations, 1999-2000 (Box-folder 100: 14)
  - Shikaki, Khalil, 1995-2002 (Box-folder 100: 15)
  - Siegman, Henry, 2002-2003 (Box-folder 100: 16)
  - Sudan, 2000-2001 (Box-folder 100: 17)
  - Syria, 1980-2003
    - 1980 (Box-folder 101: 1)
    - 1990-1997 (Box-folder 101: 2-3)
    - 1998-2000 (Box-folder 101: 4-5)
    - 2001-2003 (Box-folder 101: 6)
  - Taba negotiations, 2001 (Box-folder 101: 7)
  - Turkey, 1957-2002
    - 1957-1988 (Box-folder 101: 8)
    - 1996-2002 (Box-folder 101: 9-10)
  - United States-Foreign relations, 1991-2001 (Box-folder 101: 11)
  - Water in the Middle East, 1961-2001
    - 1961-1965 (Box-folder 102: 1)
    - 1991 (Box-folder 102: 2)
    - 1992 (Box-folder 102: 3)
    - 1993-1998 (Box-folder 102: 4)
    - 2000-2001 (Box-folder 102: 5)
  - Wye Memorandum, 1998-1999
    - 1998 (Box-folder 102: 6)
    - 1998-1999 (Box-folder 102: 7)
  - Yemen, 2000-2001 (Box-folder 102: 8)
- Speeches and writings, 1942-1999
  - "Arab Politics in Palestine," Contemporary Jewish Record, 1942 December (Box-folder 102: 9)
  - "Recent Books on the Problem of Palestine," The Middle East Journal, 1949 January (Box-folder 102: 10)
  - Notes on Near and Middle East history, 1950 (Box-folder 102: 11-12)
  - Notes on Near and Middle East history, 1950 (Box-folder 103: 1-6)
  - "Crisis in the Arab East," Foreign Policy Reports, 1950 March 1 (Box-folder 103: 7)
  - "United States Policies on Palestine," Publications of the Jewish Historical Society, 1950 December (Box-folder 103: 8)
  - "Middle East Muddle," The Nation, 1950 December 16 (Box-folder 103: 9)
  - "Arab-Israel Tensions,", 1951 (Box-folder 103: 10)
  - "The Israeli-Syrian Crisis in the Light of the Arab-Israel Armistice System," International Organization, volume 5, no. 3, 1951 (Box-folder 103: 11)
  - "Syrian-Israeli Clashes Jeopardize Palestine Armistice," Foreign Policy Bulletin, 1951 August 17 (Box-folder 103: 12)
  - "Unity and Disunity in the Middle East," International Conciliation, 1952 May (Box-folder 103: 13)
  - "The United Nations Conciliation Commission for Palestine: Establishment and Definition of Functions," volume 7, no. 4, 1953 (Box-folder 103: 14)
  - "Britain, Egypt and the Sudan," Foreign Policy Bulletin, 1953 March 15 (Box-folder 103: 15)
  - "Our Mistakes in the Middle East," The Atlantic Monthly, 1956 December (Box-folder 103: 16)
  - Encyclopedia entries on Iran and Iraq, 1958 (Box-folder 103: 17)
  - Encyclopedia entry on Egypt, 1958 (Box-folder 103: 18)
  - Encyclopedia entry on Jordan, 1958 (Box-folder 103: 19)
  - Encyclopedia entry on Lebanon, 1958 (Box-folder 103: 20)
  - Encyclopedia entryon Saudi Arabia, 1958 (Box-folder 103: 21)
  - Encyclopedia entry on Sudan, 1958 (Box-folder 103: 22)
  - Encyclopedia entry on Syria, 1958 (Box-folder 103: 23)
  - Encyclopedia entry on the Arabian peninsula, 1958 (Box-folder 103: 24)
  - Encyclopedia entry on Yemen, 1958 (Box-folder 103: 25)
  - Encyclopedia entry on Israel, 1960 (Box-folder 103: 26)
  - Encyclopedia entry on the United Arab Republic, 1961 (Box-folder 103: 27)
  - "The Europeanization of Ottoman Diplomacy: The Conversion from Unilateralism to Reciprocity in the Nineteenth Century," Belleten, 1961 July (Box-folder 103: 28)
  - The Middle East and North Africa in World Politics: A Documentary Record, volumes one and two, and projected volume three, 1961-1980
    - Correspondence, 1961-1980
      - 1961-1972 (Box-folder 103: 29)
      - 1973-1978 (Box-folder 103: 30)
      - 1979-1980 (Box-folder 103: 31)
    - Acknowledgements, 1974 (Box-folder 104: 1)
    - Preface, 1974 (Box-folder 104: 2)
    - Table of contents, 1978 (Box-folder 104: 3)
  - Speech on the Middle East, St. Louis, Missouri, 1962 (Box-folder 104: 4)
  - "Crucial Factors in the Middle East," lecture, Institute for Religious and Social Studies, New York City, 1962 January 23 (Box-folder 104: 5)
  - "Russia and the Turkish Straits: A Revaluation of the Origins of the Problem," World Politics, 1962 July (Box-folder 104: 6)
  - "The Role of the Military in Society and Government in Israel,", 1963 (Box-folder 104: 7)
  - "The UN and Disimperialism in the Middle East," International Organization, volume XIX, no. 3, 1965 (Box-folder 104: 8)
  - Fixing the pattern, 1966 (Box-folder 104: 9)
  - Entry on the Arab League, Crowell-Collier Encyclopedia, 1967 (Box-folder 104: 10)
  - "The Coming Political Elite in Israel,", 1967 April 24 (Box-folder 104: 11)
  - "The Soviet Search for Strategic Mobility in the Meditteranean: Focus on a Lingering Cold War,", 1967 October 26 (Box-folder 104: 12)
  - "The Soviet Quest for Strategic Mobility in the Mediterranean: Focus of a Lingering Cold War,", 1968 January 16 (Box-folder 104: 13)
  - "The Lingering Soviet-American Cold War in the Middle East,", 1968 January 30 (Box-folder 104: 14)
  - "Origins of the Rivalry," Proceedings of the Academy of Political Science, volume 29, no. 3, 1969 (Box-folder 104: 15)
  - Changing Military Perspectives in the Middle East, 1969-1970
    - Correspondence, 1970 (Box-folder 104: 16)
    - First draft, 1969 June (Box-folder 104: 17)
    - Second draft, 1969 August (Box-folder 104: 18)
    - Third draft, 1970 February (Box-folder 104: 19)
    - Final draft, 1970 July (Box-folder 104: 20)
    - Printed copy, 1970 (Box-folder 104: 21)
  - "Reflections on European Imperialism and Social Change: The Experience of the Middle East,", 1971 (Box-folder 105: 1)
  - "Reopening a Dialogue," with Jacques Vernant, 1971 (Box-folder 105: 2)
  - "Changing Military Perspectives in the Middle East," in Paul Y. Hammond and Sidney S. Alexander (eds.), Political Dynamics in the Middle East, 1972 (Box-folder 105: 3)
  - "The Persian Gulf: British Withdrawal and Western Security," The Annals of the American Academy of Political and Social Science, 1972 May (Box-folder 105: 4)
  - "Superpower Rivalry and the Arab-Israel Dispute: Involvement or Commitment?" in M. Confino and S. Shamir (eds.), The USSR and the Middle East, 1973 (Box-folder 105: 5)
  - "Weapons Acquisition: Israel and Egypt,", 1973 January (Box-folder 105: 6)
  - "The Persian Gulf after the Pax Britannica: Choices for United States in the Coming Decade,", 1973 April 23 (Box-folder 105: 7)
  - "'Partners and Adversaries' in the Middle East," transcript of testimony before the Subcommittee on the Near East and South Asia, House Committee on Foreign Affairs, Washington, D.C., 1973 November 1 (Box-folder 105: 8)
  - Address, Iran America Society Returnee Association, 1974 January 9 (Box-folder 105: 9)
  - "Developments and Issues in the Persian Gulf," presentation at the National War College, Washington, D.C., 1974 March 21 (Box-folder 105: 10)
  - "Britain and Ottoman Palestine: An Impressionistic Retrospect," in M. Ma'oz (ed.), Studies on Palestine during the Ottoman Period, 1975 (Box-folder 105: 11)
  - Introduction to paperback edition, The Struggle for Palestine, 1976 (Box-folder 105: 12)
  - "The Pervasive Crisis," in J. C. Hurewitz (ed.), Oil, the Arab-Israel Dispute, and the Industrial World: Horizons of Crisis, 1976 (Box-folder 105: 13)
  - "Political Instability in the Arab-Israel Zone and the Arms-Transfer Issue,", 1976 September 15 (Box-folder 105: 14)
  - Transcript of remarks, National Jewish Community Relations Advisory Council conference, 1977 March (Box-folder 105: 15)
  - "Arab Regional Politics and the Dispute with Israel: Changing Foci after Sadat's Visit to Jerusalem,", 1978 July 12 (Box-folder 105: 16)
  - "High-Decibel Politics: The United States and the Middle East,", 1983 April 12 (Box-folder 105: 17)
  - The Persian Gulf: After Iran's Revolution, 1979 (Box-folder 105: 18)
  - "Washington as Middle East Peaceseeker,", 1993 (Box-folder 105: 19)
  - Review of Geoffrey Wheatcroft, The Controversy of Zion: Jewish Nationalism, the Jewish State, and the Unresolved Jewish Dilemma, 1996 (Box-folder 105: 20)
  - Notes for seminar on Israeli elections, 1999 May 12 (Box-folder 105: 21)
- Academic career file, 1949-2003
  - Class notes, 1951-1961
    - 1951-1956 (Box-folder 105: 22)
    - 1957 (Box-folder 106: 1)
    - 1961 (Box-folder 106: 2)
  - Clippings, 1965-1970 (Box-folder 106: 3)
  - Conferences and seminars file, 1949-1999 (Box-folder 106: 4)
  - Correspondence, 1957-2003
    - General, 1957-2003
      - 1957-1970 (Box-folder 106: 5)
      - 1971-2003 (Box-folder 106: 6)
    - Iran-U.S. Claims Tribunal, 1994 (Box-folder 106: 7)
  - Document procurement file, 1969-1979
    - 1969-1971 (Box-folder 106: 8)
    - 1973-1979 (Box-folder 106: 9)
  - Photographs, 1980 (Box-folder 106: 10)
  - Summaries of meetings with officials and academics, 1967-1977 (Box-folder 106: 11)
- Printed matter, 1910-1997
  - Monographs, 1910-1997 (Box-folder 107: 1-15)
  - Pamphlets, 1940-1979
    - 1940-1952 (Box-folder 107: 16)
    - 1953-1973 (Box-folder 107: 17)
    - 1977-1979 (Box-folder 107: 19)
- Photocopies of British Foreign Office documents relating to Persia, 1836-1926
  - 1836 (Box-folder 108: 1)
  - 1857-1874 (Box-folder 108: 2)
  - 1874-1880 (Box-folder 108: 3)
  - 1892 (Box-folder 108: 4)
  - 1919 (Box-folder 108: 5)
  - 1920 (Box-folder 108: 6)
  - 1921 (Box-folder 108: 7)
  - 1926 (Box-folder 108: 8)
- Declassified U.S. government records, 1945-1946, 1967
  Formerly security-classified records of the U.S. government, released in full or in part. Arranged chronologically by date of release by Hoover.
  - 2015 July release of records, 1945-1946, 1967 (Box-folder 108: 9)
    Declassified records, including reports related to Palestine, Trans-Jordan, Turkey, and Iran.
- Card file with bibliography of works published on Middle East history and politics, 1980 (Box-folder 109: 1)
- Oversize materials, 1926-1967
  - Photocopies of British government documents from the Public Records Office, 1926-1966
    - 1926-1934 (Box-folder 110: 1)
    - 1943-1944 (Box-folder 110: 2)
    - 1945 (Box-folder 110: 3-5)
    - 1945-1946 (Box-folder 110: 6)
    - 1946 (Box-folder 110: 7-9)
    - 1946-1947 (Box-folder 111: 1)
    - 1947 (Box-folder 111: 2-4)
    - 1948 (Box-folder 111: 5-11)
    - 1949 (Box-folder 112: 1-2)
    - 1950 (Box-folder 111: 3)
    - 1953 (Box-folder 112: 4-5)
    - 1954 (Box-folder 112: 6-8)
    - 1955 (Box-folder 112: 9)
    - 1955 (Box-folder 113: 1-2)
    - 1956 (Box-folder 113: 3-9)
    - 1956 (Box-folder 114: 1-5)
    - 1957 (Box-folder 114: 6-9)
    - 1958 (Box-folder 114: 10)
    - 1966 (Box-folder 114: 11)
  - Proclamation issued by British authorities in Palestine, 1945 November 15 (Map case)
  - Maps of the Persian Gulf and Middle East region, prepared by the U.S. Navy, 1949-1967 (Map case)